DÜSSELDORF METROPOLITAN POLICE HOLDING CELLS
POLICJA MIEJSKA W DÜSSELDORFIE ARESZT
Tell Helene and Gustav to record Detective Forster for me.
Poproś Helenę i Gustava, aby nagrali dla mnie Detektywa Forstera.
What?
Co?
They play reruns of it every Tuesday at 10 a.m.
Grają powtórki w każdy wtorek o 10.00.
Ain't you seen it? It's a great show!
Nie widziałeś? Świetny serial.
Milch, this isn't the time to be messing around.
Milch, nie czas na wygłupy.
Do you have any idea how much trouble
Wiesz, ile przez ciebie szef ma kłopotów,
you caused the boss when you screwed up and got caught?
bo nawaliłeś i dałeś się złapać?
Even though you're such a dimwit, he still sent me to be your lawyer.
Jesteś durniem, ale i tak mnie wysłał, abym był twoim adwokatem.
Show the boss some appreciation.
Doceń to.
That's right. Now listen, Milch.
W rzeczy samej. Posłuchaj, Milch.
You do know what will happen if you talk, right?
Wiesz, co się stanie, jak zaczniesz sypać?
Don't get your shorts in a knot. I'd never backstab my buddies.
Już się tak nie spinaj. Nie zdradzam swoich kumpli.
Fine, I'll believe you.
Dobra, wierzę ci.
Now just confess according to the script I've given you. Got it?
Po prostu zeznawaj zgodnie z moim scenariuszem. Dobrze?
I'm more interested in knowing when my next job will be.
Bardziej mnie ciekawi, kiedy będzie moja następna robota.
Your next job? Don't you know how long you're going to be in?
Następna? Wiesz, jak długo będziesz siedzieć?
Get real!
Bądź realistą.
-You're the ones who need to get real. -Huh?
- To wy bądźcie realistami. - Co?
Just who do you think I am?
Za kogo wy mnie uważacie?
I'm Gunther Milch, the king of prison breaks.
Jestem Gunther Milch, król ucieczek z więzienia.
I don't have time for your garbage.
Nie mam czasu na twoje bzdury.
Listen. If you confess according to my script, you'll get out in five years.
Trzymaj się mojego scenariusza, a wyjdziesz za pięć lat.
-Make sure you tell them. -Huh?
- Przekaż im. - Co?
Like I just said,
Jak mówiłem,
tell Helene and Gustav to record Detective Forster.
przekaż Helenie i Gustavowi, żeby nagrali Detektywa Forstera.
But those guys aren't very reliable.
Ci kolesie nie są zbyt wiarygodni.
I should probably try one more time while I'm at this station.
Warto znów spróbować, dopóki jestem na tym komisariacie.
Try what?
Co takiego?
I bet he's faking it again.
Pewnie znów udaje.
Are you sure?
Tak myślisz?
There was blood in his vomit and he feels really cold.
Miał krew w wymiocinach i jest bardzo zimny.
-Don't puke here! -Doctor!
- Nie wymiotuj tutaj! - Doktorze!
You have good timing!
Doskonałe wyczucie czasu!
I need you to watch this place.
Pilnujcie gabinetu. Aresztowano jakichś gnojków,
But this guy looks like he's about to die.
Ten gość wygląda, jakby miał umrzeć.
Milch again, huh?
Znów Milch?
Put him on that bed. I'll check him out later.
Połóż go na łóżku. Potem go zbadam.
No way! Take me to the hospital!
Nie ma mowy. Weźcie mnie do szpitala!
I'll be back soon. Just sit tight.
Niedługo wracam. Siedź spokojnie. Kurcze, tylko przybywa chorych.
You've got to be kidding!
No bez jaj!
What the hell's that serial killer doing in the next bed?
Co, do cholery, robi seryjny morderca w sąsiednim łóżku?
Quit whining!
Przestań jęczeć!
He collapsed because he hasn't been eating, so I gave him an IV.
Osłabł, bo nie jada. Dostał więc kroplówkę.
That guy being near me is just making me even sicker!
Czuję się jeszcze gorzej, bo ten gość leży obok mnie!
Shut up and lie still!
Leż już cicho!
Doctor, you said people were injured. How many are there?
Doktorze, mówił pan, że są ranni. Ilu?
How should I know? I won't know till I get there.
Skąd mam wiedzieć. Dowiem się na miejscu.
Dammit! I'll make those young punks pay later!
Kurde! Jeszcze pokażę tym gnojkom.
About what you said before…
Jeśli chodzi o to, co mówiłeś…
I'd like your help.
Pomóż mi.
I want to escape.
Chciałbym uciec.
I think I'm going to kill…
Myślę, że zabiję…
your ex-fiancée, Eva Heinemann.
pana byłą narzeczoną, Evę Heinemann.
So, what do you think?
Co pan na to?
Wouldn't you agree that it's a good idea?
Nie uważa pan, że to dobry pomysł?
I mean, she knows far too much.
Wie zdecydowanie za dużo.
On that rainy day, she was at the building under construction.
W tamten deszczowy dzień była na placu budowy.
She heard three shots fired and saw…
Usłyszała trzy strzały i zobaczyła…
him.
go.
We don't need people like her.
Nie potrzebujemy takich ludzi jak ona.
We don't, do we?
Prawda?
Don't…
Nie…
Don't!
Nie rób tego!
She… Eva would never testify to that!
Eva nigdy nie zezna przeciwko niemu.
All she wants is for me to be thrown in prison forever!
Chce tylko, żebym zgnił w więzieniu.
She simply wants me to regret dumping her for the rest of my life!
Mam do końca moich dni żałować, że ją rzuciłem!
She'll only testify to things that'll hurt me!
Zezna tylko to, co mi zaszkodzi!
So… that's why…
Dlatego…
So that's why I asked you if you agreed that it was a good idea.
Dlatego zapytałem, czy uważa pan, że to dobry pomysł.
With her out of the way,
Gdy się jej pozbędę,
you could get out of going to prison.
może wydostanie się pan z więzienia.
It would be very good for us, as well as for you if she died.
Dobrze byłoby dla nas, a także dla pana, gdyby zginęła.
Are you going to tell the cops?
Powie pan glinom?
Do you think they'd believe that kind of story?
Myśli pan, że uwierzą w taką historyjkę?
Or are you going to tell the lawyer Mr. Verdemann?
A może powie pan mecenasowi Verdemannowi?
He and I might be working together, you know.
Być może będę z nim współpracować.
We talented lawyers will get you pronounced innocent.
My, zdolni prawnicy, zadbamy o to, aby ogłosili pana niewinnym.
Once you're cleared and get out, you'll be able to enjoy a nice drink.
Po oczyszczeniu z zarzutów i uwolnieniu może się pan rozluźnić przy drinku.
By that time,
Do tego czasu
that miserable, stuck up, loud-mouthed has-been will be long gone.
ta nędzna, nadęta, pyskata, podupadła panna zniknie na dobre.
I want to escape.
Chcę uciec.
You got to be kidding me!
To jakieś kpiny! Nie chcę leżeć obok tego cholernego mordercy!
Hey, Milch! Shut your trap!
Milch! Stul pysk!
What do I care if you never confess to your murders!
Nikogo mnie obchodzi, że nie przyznasz się do zabójstw!
Milch!
Milch!
I confessed up to what I did,
Ja się przyznałem,
and now I'll get sent to jail within five days!
teraz w ciągu pięciu dni wyślą mnie do więzienia!
I'm glad I won't have to be stuck with a murderer like you!
Dobrze, że nie utknę tu z takim mordercą jak ty.
-Quit your damn shouting! -Milch!
- Dość tych wrzasków! - Milch!
You're perfectly healthy!
Jesteś idealnie zdrowy!
Come with us! I knew you were faking it!
Idziesz z nami! Wiedziałem, że udajesz.
I can hardly wait!
Już się nie mogę doczekać!
I've only got to put up with five more days with this goddamn murderer!
Jeszcze tylko pięć dni z tym cholernym mordercą!
Enough of you!
Dość już tego!
Shut up, dammit!
Milcz, ty cholero!
Within five days, huh?
W ciągu pięciu dni, tak?
On that rainy day,
Tego deszczowego dnia
you heard three shots fired in a building that was under construction
usłyszała pani trzy strzały na placu budowy.
and saw a young blonde man come down the stairs.
Zobaczyła pani, jak młody blondyn zszedł ze schodów.
That's correct, isn't it?
Zgadza się?
That's right.
Tak.
How about it?
I co?
Do you still plan on ignoring the existence of Johan?
Wciąż planuje pan udawać, że Johan nie istnieje?
I don't know.
Nie wiem.
Eva Heinemann,
Evo Heinemann,
will you testify to this in court?
zezna to pani w sądzie?
No way.
Nie ma mowy.
DÜSSELDORF METROPOLITAN POLICE
MIEJSKA POLICJA
What do you think Dr. Tenma wants to talk to us this late at night for?
Jak pan myśli? Po co doktor Tenma wezwał nas tak późno?
Why does he want to talk now?
Dlaczego teraz chce rozmawiać?
I don't know. But he said he had to talk to the investigators.
Nie wiem. Twierdził, że musi pogadać ze śledczymi.
What is it you want to tell us, Dr. Tenma?
Co nam pan chciał powiedzieć, doktorze Tenma?
In Düsseldorf at Eisler Memorial Hospital,
W Düsseldorfie w Szpitalu Klinicznym im. Eislera
Director Heinemann…
dyrektor Heinemann…
Director of Surgery Oppenheimer, Dr. Boyer…
ordynator chirurgii Oppenheimer, doktor Boyer…
and my patient, Adolf Junkers…
i mój pacjent, Adolf Junkers…
I… killed them.
Zabiłem ich.
I… killed all of them.
Zabiłem wszystkich.
The wind blew.
Powiało.
The thermos tumbled over.
Termosy się przewróciły.
The sandwiches got covered in dirt.
Kanapki były całe w ziemi.
Then he…
Wtedy on…
smiled sadly.
uśmiechnął się smutno.
According to a police announcement,
Według komunikatu policji
in the early hours of the fourth,
rano czwartego tego miesiąca
the suspect Kenzo Tenma, who had denied his guilt
podejrzany Kenzo Tenma, który dotąd nie przyznawał się do winy
has changed his story regarding the murders
zmienił zeznania w sprawie morderstw
at Eisler Memorial Hospital in Düsseldorf of the hospital director,
w Szpitalu Klinicznym im. Eislera w Düsseldorfie – jego dyrektora,
two other doctors, and Adolf Junkers.
dwóch innych lekarzy i Adolfa Junkersa.
He has confessed to all their killings.
Przyznał się do ich zamordowania.
That can't be!
Niemożliwe!
This news is just in.
Z ostatniej chwili…
He confessed? Why?
Przyznał się? Dlaczego?
…in the early hours of the fourth,
…rano czwartego podejrzany Kenzo Tenma, który dotąd twierdził, że jest niewinny,
has confessed that he perpetrated all the crimes he's charged with.
przyznał się do wszystkich zarzucanych mu zbrodni.
I won't stand for this!
Nie pozwolę na to!
What the heck did you do to Dr. Tenma?
Co zrobiliście doktorowi Tenmie?
What kind of torture did you put him through
Jak go torturowaliście, że przyznał się do tych zbrodni?
Why don't you let go of me?
Może mnie pan puścić?
Enough of this! I demand to see Tenma right now!
Dość tego! Chcę natychmiast widzieć Tenmę!
I'll talk to him myself and find out
Porozmawiam z nim i dowiem się,
what you put him through during interrogation!
co mu zrobiliście podczas przesłuchań!
It's pointless, Dr. Reichwein.
To nic nie da, doktorze Reichwein.
What?
Co?
He won't even let me, his own lawyer, see him.
Nie dopuszcza mnie, swojego adwokata, do siebie.
It appears that he confessed to the crimes all on his own.
Wygląda na to, że sam przyznał się do zbrodni.
That's just not possible!
To wykluczone!
I asked around.
Popytałem.
I know the investigators.
Znam tych śledczych.
They could never torture anyone.
Nigdy nikogo nie torturowali.
Tenma confessed quite easily.
Tenma z łatwością się przyznał.
So easily, it was surprising.
Zadziwiająco łatwo.
Mr. Verdemann!
Panie Verdemann!
Don't tell me even you think that his confession is genuine!
Myśli pan, że jego wyznania są szczere?
Unless I can interview him, I won't know why he's done this.
Bez porozmawiania z nim nie dowiem się, dlaczego to zrobił.
I believe in him!
Wierzę w niego!
Dr. Tenma is innocent!
Doktor Tenma jest niewinny!
Hello? Verdemann here.
Halo? Mówi Verdemann.
Oh, Mr. Baul.
- Ach, panie Baul. - Bardzo mi przykro.
Something suddenly came up so I couldn't go with you.
Coś mi wypadło i nie mogłem przyjechać.
It's okay.
W porządku.
How did it go? Did Dr. Tenma really confess?
Jak poszło? Pan Tenma naprawdę się przyznał?
Yes, he also refused to see me.
Tak. Odmówił też spotkania się ze mną.
That's a real pity.
Wielka szkoda.
We, lawyers, were working so hard to prove his innocence
My, prawnicy, ciężko pracujemy, żeby udowodnić jego niewinność
and that he was falsely accused, but then he goes and confesses.
w sprawie o niesłuszne oskarżenie, a on nagle się przyznaje.
In that regard, your father was very admirable.
Pod tym względem pana ojciec był godny szacunku.
No matter how harsh the interrogations were,
Nieważne, jak brutalnie go przesłuchiwano,
he never succumbed,
nigdy nie uległ.
and always claimed his innocence.
Zawsze podkreślał swoją niewinność.
And he was innocent.
I był niewinny.
So then, what would you like to do now, Mr. Verdemann?
Zatem, panie Verdemann, jakie dalsze kroki?
Mr. Verdemann?
Panie Verdemann?
What? Sorry.
Co? Przepraszam.
What about that woman? What was her name again?
Co z tą kobietą? Jak się nazywała?
That woman who can prove Tenma's innocence.
Tą, która może udowodnić niewinność Tenmy?
Right. Her name's Eva Heinemann.
No tak. Eva Heinemann.
Where is she now?
Gdzie teraz jest?
At a hotel in the city.
W hotelu w mieście.
I'd like to talk to her.
Chciałbym z nią porozmawiać.
You'd better not. She's rather difficult to deal with.
Lepiej nie. Jest niełatwa w obyciu.
I'll meet with her again, alone this time.
Spotkam się znów z nią. Tym razem sam.
My father was admirable, huh?
Mój ojciec godny szacunku, tak?
Open up, Eva Heinemann.
Proszę otworzyć, Evo Heinemann.
I know you're inside.
Wiem, że pani tam jest.
The maids told me that you've been in there drinking
Pokojówki mówią, że pije pani od rana
all day long so they can't even make up the bed.
i nie mogą nawet pościelić łóżka.
Ms. Heinemann,
Pani Heinemann,
I am fully aware that you despise Dr. Tenma.
mam pełną świadomość, że nie cierpi pani doktora Tenmy.
Even after the loss of your father, the director,
Po śmierci ojca, dyrektora,
if your relationship with Dr. Tenma had continued,
gdyby pani związek z doktorem Tenmą przetrwał,
you would have had a very satisfying life.
miałaby pani bardzo wygodne życie.
However, Dr. Tenma left you.
Ale on panią opuścił.
I'd agree that Dr. Tenma threw your life into turmoil.
Zgodzę się, że zakłócił całe pani życie.
My father…
Mojego ojca…
My father was tossed into prison as a spy.
Mojego ojca wysłano do więzienia jako szpiega.
For many years, I was shunned and looked upon as the son of a spy.
Przez wiele lat byłem wyrzutkiem, synem szpiega.
My life was thrown into turmoil by my father.
Ojciec zakłócił całe moje życie.
But I didn't succumb.
Ale nie uległem temu.
Do you know why?
Wie pani dlaczego?
Do you know why I was able to fight back?
Wie pani, dlaczego byłem w stanie walczyć?
Because I believed in him.
Bo mu wierzyłem.
I believed my father was innocent.
Wierzyłem, że ojciec jest niewinny.
My father was innocent.
Mój ojciec był niewinny.
My father was innocent!
Mój ojciec był niewinny!
Innocent…
Niewinny…
The people I believe in must be innocent!
Osoby, w których wierzę, muszą być niewinne!
I will prove that Tenma is innocent!
Udowodnię, że Tenma jest niewinny!
Tenma must be innocent!
Tenma musi być niewinny!
Just like my father must be innocent as well!
Tak samo jak mój ojciec musiał być niewinny!
Those are me and my partner's phone numbers.
To telefon do mnie i mojego partnera.
Contact us if you decide to testify.
Proszę dać znać, jeśli postanowi pani zeznawać.
What's that? He's being transferred to jail tomorrow?
Co? Jutro go przewiozą do więzienia?
But it's only been a few days since he arrived!
Przyjechał zaledwie kilka dni temu.
It's because Tenma's confession has gone incredibly smoothly.
To dlatego, że doktor Tenma tak łatwo się przyznał.
Isn't there anything you can do, Mr. Verdemann?
Nie może pan nic zrobić, panie Verdemann?
Even the police are doing what they can to convince Tenma to let us see him.
Nawet policja próbuje namówić go, żeby się z nami spotkał.
By the way, where's Eva Heinemann?
- Swoją drogą, gdzie jest Eva Heinemann? - Wyszła.
What?
Co?
She's probably getting blind drunk at some bar again.
Pewnie znów pije na umór w jakimś barze.
Düsseldorf…
Düsseldorf…
It's all the same stinking places.
Wszędzie takie same prześmierdłe dziury.
I hate this town.
Nie cierpię tego miasta.
You're here.
To ty!
I've been sitting here for the last five minutes.
Siedzę tu od pięciu minut.
I'm sorry.
Przepraszam.
This is a fascinating paper, so I was copying it.
To fascynujący artykuł, więc go kopiuję.
Why don't we go somewhere else?
Może pójdziemy gdzie indziej?
I know, let's get something to eat.
Wiem. Chodźmy coś zjeść.
Where do you want to go? An Italian place? Or maybe French?
Gdzie chciałabyś pójść? Włoska knajpa? Francuska?
-Gee, don't let me bother you. -What?
- Już nie przeszkadzam. - Co?
You may as well keep copying it.
Wracaj do kopiowania.
Wait! Eva!
Czekaj! Evo!
Eva!
Evo!
I'm glad you like it.
Fajnie, że smakuje.
Pretty good, isn't it?
Dobre, co?
What are you doing?
Co robisz?
Well, putting a stone here will keep it from blowing away.
Kładę kamień, żeby nam nie wywiało.
That's not what I mean. Why are you putting the blanket here?
Nie o to mi chodzi. Dlaczego rozkładasz tu koc?
It's nice for a change to have lunch in a place like this.
Fajnie dla odmiany zjeść lunch w takim miejscu.
The weather's nice too.
Pogoda też jest ładna.
Who's having lunch here?
Kto zje tu lunch?
We are. I made us sandwiches. I hope you like them.
My. Zrobiłem nam kanapki. Mam nadzieję, że będą ci smakować.
There are bugs everywhere.
- Tu są owady. - Damy sobie radę.
This is ridiculous.
Jakiś idiotyzm.
They're covered in dirt.
Są całe w ziemi.
They're ruined.
Do niczego.
You want one too, lady?
Pani też chce jedną?
Franz, don't bother her.
- Franzie, nie zaczepiaj. - Nie bądź niegrzeczny.
Thank you.
Dziękuję.
Good, isn't it?
Dobra, co?
Walk.
Naprzód.
Get in.
Wsiadać.
Hello?
Halo?
I wasn't able to get through to Mr. Verdemann.
Nie udało mi się złapać pana Verdemanna, więc zadzwoniłam do pana.
I see. His wife's about ready to give birth,
Rozumiem. Żona pewnie niebawem urodzi.
so he's probably at the hospital.
Pewnie jest w szpitalu.
He's told me about you though, Eva Heinemann.
Opowiadał mi o pani, Evo Heinemann.
Feel free to ask me anything you like.
Proszę pytać o cokolwiek.
I think I'll do it.
Chyba to zrobię.
Do what?
Co takiego?
I'll testify to prove Tenma's innocence.
Złożę zeznania, aby udowodnić niewinność Tenmy.
Is that right? That would be fantastic.
Doprawdy? Byłoby wspaniale.
So, what hotel are you staying at?
A w jakim hotelu pani jest?
All right.
Dobrze.
I'll be there right away.
Już tam jadę.